{
  "reference_number": "11505",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "New Zealand needs to set an ambitious target now as we only have one earth to live in. We need to act now to make changes to our\n net carbon emissions and drive a change as soon as possible."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": "Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050 (or sooner) is the only way to go. This story of why we are going for this\n\n target needs to be told in good narratives to everyone in New Zealand."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "This target is our target and should not use emissions reductions from international carbon units. Its time we as New Zealanders\n used our own country to reduce emissions rather than relying on international credit."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Various crisis such as the Global Financial Crisis (which was good and actually reduced carbon emissions), War (which could increase\n\n carbon emissions) and disasters caused by climate change or natural should not provide a reason to revise our carbon target. The\n whole point is to have a long term 30 year commitment to where we are going. Its like a saving account or kiwisaver you know where\n you would like to get to so you save accordingly no matter what. We we don't have this attitude we will not reach the target. Its also\n\n important to lock it in so future government reduce or stop the target in future on the pretext that we have crisis."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Setting the target forward is really important and the only way this will work. All of New Zealand needs to know where they are heading\n\n and what and why are zero emissions target is for."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The future generations of New Zealand need to be considered in setting plans to meet the budgets. Consultation needs to occur\n\nwith the children of New Zealand in a meaningful manner so that their voice is heard even if they can not vote for the government at\nthe time."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "The Climate Change Commissioner needs the expertise on p45 Our Climate Your Say. However it also needs expertise is working with\n\nand supporting youth leadership and consultation. Its the youth of today who are going to be working in the future on the targets. If\nthe Climate Change Commissioner does not get working with Youth right it will not happen in the future."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "We definitely need to be working on adaptation to climate change as we will be facing some major environmental changes in the\n\nfuture."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Thank you for allowing everyone in New Zealand to submit on this discussion document in different ways and in different forms.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
